

Mukesh Kumar Ranjan

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

WHO AM I AT A GLANCE

I have been working with web development since 2014, the period during which I have worked in different environments from big MNC to starts-ups. I am a self-motivated and self taught professional who likes to solve real world problems in the domain of web and software development with experience handling multiple projects utilising my team management skills.

WHY HIRE ME?

- I'm a **result-oriented** web application developer with considerable training and hands-on project building experience in all stages of design, coding, and testing of web applications.
- I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital world experience. My repertoire includes programming languages and tools such as JS, AJAX, JQuery, PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, NodeJs, Bootstrap, Github etc.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

#SCHOOL OF ACCELERATED LEARNING, HYD Product Engineering - (June - December) 2020

• Completed and Graduated with all the 11 MVP's built using Javascript and Node Js framework technology.

#PUNJAB TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, JALANDHAR Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering - August 2010 to June 2014

• Graduated with a bachelors degree that equipped me with the knowledge of web fundamentals, programming languages and operating systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#CONCENTRIX DAKSH SERVICES INDIA PVT. LTD. Senior Advisor | April 2017 to February 2020

- Worked on Multiple Client Projects "Machine Learning", "Revue Tool - UI-UX" & "LMS Systems".
- Creating & Maintaining various database related tasks.
- Resolving multiple **bugs/issues** & meet project **deadlines**.

Bucket Lead | June 2015 to March 2017

- Handled team and successfully developed UI-UX for web.
- Converting **designs** to relevant **responsive websites**.
- **Integrating** modules and working with different API's.

#INNOVATIVE TRAINING PLACE, NEW DELHI SEO & Data Analyst | November 2014 to May 2015

- Handled web development and Client SEO Activities.
- Worked on 20 applications & Managed databases.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

• Web Technologies - Frameworks - DataBases

JavaScript Express.Js MongoDB PHP Node.Is PostgreSQL

• Web Servers - Version Control - Cloud Platform

NGINX Github Heroku Netlify **AWS** Github Pages

Additional Technical Competencies

HTML CSS Web Sockets JQuery React.Js Photoshop Shell Scripting Open Source

LATEST PROJECTS

#WEBDEVPOOL - A DEVELOPERS COMMUNITY Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Mongo DB

- Built a professional network for developers where they can share their skills, experiences, education and showcase their 5 recent github repositories with other developers worldwide.
- Users can create their profiles, publish posts, like posts and can make comments in post.
- Created Back-end API and worked on integration for the webdevpool application.
- Managed the team and designed the website wire-framing from the scratch with the idea.

#AUTHORSBLOG - A BLOGGING PLATFORM Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Mongo DB

- Built a guest blogging platform for authors and bloggers who want to promote their online business by writing articles in this platform.
- Users can sign-in/up, create their profiles and publish their posts, comment and like also.
- Lead the team, designed the website wire-framing and created back-end API for product.

#IMGUP - AN IMAGE UPLOADING APPLICATION

Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Firebase

- Simulated the popular image sharing web application imgur.com.
- Users can upload single or multiple images and after that they will get a notification in the bar.
- Created the entire back-end API, Integrated frontend and done testing for this web application.

(Dial: (+91) 783-881-0985

